Scrpbk
The College of Saint Rose Archives
Scrapbook Collection
1920-1997
Scrpbk
The College of Saint Rose Archives
18.0 Linear feet (42 boxes)
This is a collection of scrapbooks created by former students and faculty. The subjects range from general academic years to specific events.
Related Archival Materials note
There is also an "Officical College Scrapbook Collection" that includes large scrapbooks of newspaper clippings.
- Scrapbook 01, 1921-1927; Cloth binding (good condition, missing bottom tie); Both fixed and loose items; Maas, Anita, (1925) (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes: Calendar, Correspondence, Dance Cards, Dance Favors, Memorabilia, Newspaper Clippings, Personal Items, Photographs
  Dances, proms, and balls; Rose Day
- Scrapbook 02, 1921-1927; Cloth binding (good condition, missing top tie); Both fixed and loose items; Maas, Anita, (1925) (Box 2, Box 3)
  Includes: Calendar/Daybook, Correspondence, Dance Cards, Dance Favors, Memorabilia, Newspaper Clippings, Paper Memorabilia, Personal Items, Photographs
  - Items from Scrapbook 02 Items, 1921/1927 (Box 3)
    Folder List: Correspondence 1921, Class Offerings 1921-1922, Correspondence 1922, Class Offerings 1922-1923, Correspondence 1923, Correspondence 1924 [contains $1 silver certificate and check], Musicale; Rose Day Program – 1924, Class Day Programs, Commencement Programs, Graduation Repertoire Program, Rose Day Program, Annual Retreat Programs – 1924, Correspondence 1925 [contains apron from “Apron Social” and check], Card Party, Musicale, Rose Day – 1925, Correspondence 1926, Correspondence 1927, Undated Correspondence, Correspondence from Scrapbook 1, Correspondence from Scrapbook 2, Dance Cards from Scrapbook 1, Ephemera from Scrapbook 1, Ephemera from Scrapbook 2, School Papers from Scrapbook 1, Original Envelope from Scrapbook 1, Original Envelope from Scrapbook 2
- Scrapbook 03, 1940-1941; Faux-leather cover; Pages very brittle; Fixed items; Whalen, Jean, Sister, (Eleanor) (Box 4)
  Includes: Music Programs, Newspaper Clippings, Paper Memorabilia
  Rose Day
- Scrapbook 04, 1939-1940; Faux-leather cover; Pages very brittle; Fixed items; Whalen, Jean, Sister, (Eleanor) (Box 4)
  Includes: Correspondence, Drama Programs, Music Programs, Newspaper Clippings, Paper Memorabilia
  Peace Club; Rose Day
- Scrapbook 05, 1939-1941, 1968; Faux-leather cover; Fixed items; loose packet; Whalen, Jean, Sister, (Eleanor) (Box 4)
  Includes: Magazine, Photographs
  Reunions and Homecomings
- Scrapbook 06, 1927-1931, 1936, 1941; Cloth Binding; Mostly fixed items; Welsh, Helen (Box 5)
  Includes: Correspondence, Drama Programs, Football Programs, Memorabilia, Music Programs, Newspaper Clippings, Newspapers, Photographs, Theatre tickets
  Dances, proms, and balls; Reunions and Homecomings; Rose Day
- Scrapbook 07, 1986-1992; Plastic Binding; Fixed items; Faul, Karene (Box 6)
  Includes: Correspondence, Exhibit Announcements, Newspaper Clippings, Postcards
  College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Art Department.
- Scrapbook 08, 1973-1974, 1985-1992; Plastic Binding; Fixed items; Faul, Karene (Box 6)
  Includes: Correspondence, Exhibit Announcements, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs
- Scrapbook 09, 1987-1991; Faul, Karene (Box 6)
- Scrapbook 10, 1945; Plastic Cover; Some Loose Items (Box 7)
  Includes: Music Programs, Newspaper Clippings, Timelines
  25th Anniversary
- Scrapbook 11, 1955-1956; Leather Cover; Fixed Items (Box 7)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Papers
  Student Senate
- Scrapbook 12, 1960; Fixed Items (Box 7)
  Includes: Fundraising Letters, Newsletters, Newspaper Clippings, Papers, Receipt
  College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Alumni Relations Department.; Fundraising
- Scrapbook 13, 1977-1984; Fixed Items (Box 8)
  Includes: Music Programs
- Scrapbook 14, 1984-1988; Fixed Items (Box 9)
- Scrapbook 15, Bulk, 1941-1952; 1941-1952, 1979[?]; Fixed Items; Sister Agnesine (Box 10)
  Includes: Papers, Prayer Cards
  Neil Hellman Library (392 Western Avenue)
- Scrapbook 16, 1973-1976; Fixed and loose items
  Includes: Memorabilia from various classes (1920s-1970s), Newsletters, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Publicity Materials
  Alumni/ae Association; Reunions and Homecomings
- Scrapbook 17, 1924-1969; Fixed Items (Box 11)
  Includes: Programs
  Class Night; Commencement - Graduation - Baccalaureate Exercises; Moving Up Night
- Scrapbook 18, 1974; Fixed Items (Box 11)
  Includes: Certificate, Correspondence, Invitations, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Programs, Speeches
  Anniversary of First Graduation
- Scrapbook 19, 1920s; Heavy water/mold damage; Fixed Items (Box 12)
  Includes: Advertisements, Class Notes, Commencement Invitation, Commencement Programs, Correspondence, Dance Memorabilia, Newspaper Clippings, Theatre Programs, Theatre Tickets
  Commencement - Graduation - Baccalaureate Exercises; Dances, proms, and balls
- Scrapbook 20, 1953-1954; Fixed items (Box 13)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Photographs
- Scrapbook 21, 1951; Cloth cover; spiral binding (Box 13)
  Includes: 8 x 10 Photographs
- Scrapbook 22, 1980; Fixed Items; Gilroy, Rosaleen, Sister (Box 13)
  Includes: Convocation Programs, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Promotional Materials, Sixtieth Year Committee Materials
  60th Anniversary
- Scrapbook 23, 1958; Fixed Items (Box 14)
  Includes: Itinerary, Photographs, Postcards
  European Trips
- Scrapbook 24, 1970; Fixed Items, some coming loose; Sister Margaret Frances Kelly (Box 14)
  Includes: Correspondence, Fiftieth Jubilee Committee Materials, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Programs, Promotional Materials
  50th Anniversary
- Scrapbook 25, 1980-1988; Fixed and Loose Items (Box 15)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Photocopies, Schedules
  Sports
- Scrapbook 26, 1949-1959; Fixed Items (Box 16)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Photographs, Rosaverian Excerpts
- Scrapbook 27, 1959; Fixed Items (Box 16)
  Includes: Yearbook [?] Pages
- Scrapbook 28, 1960-1969; Fixed Items (Box 16)
  Includes: Keynote Excerpts, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Photographs, Rosaverian Excerpts
- Scrapbook 29, 1980; Fixed Items (Box 17)
  Includes: Fabric, Newspaper Clippings, Press Releases, Programs, Schedules
- Scrapbook 30, 1959-1964; Fixed Items (Box 17)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Timeline
  Campus Center
- Scrapbook 31, 1920-1924; Fixed Items (Box 18)
  Includes: Funeral Cards, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Programs, Regulations, Schedules
- Scrapbook 32, 1920-1978; Fixed Items (Box 18)
  Includes: CSR News, Newspaper Clippings, Programs
- Scrapbook 33, 1956-1971; Fixed Items (Box 19)
  Includes: Brochures, Itineraries, Newspaper Clippings, Press Releases, Reservation Materials
- Scrapbook 34, 1960; Fixed Items; Gilroy, Rosaleen, Sister (Box 19)
  Includes: Brochures, Cards, Correspondence, Diary, Hotel Memorabilia, Luggage Tags, Menus, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Postcards
- Scrapbook 35, 1956; Fixed Items (Box 20)
  Includes: Brochure, Diary (Sr. Benita), Itineraries, Menus, Participant List, Photographs, Postcards, Rosetta Newsletter, Ship’s Activities List
- Scrapbook 36, 1960-1961; Fixed Items (Box 20)
  Includes: Christmas Cards, Newspaper Clippings, Receipt, Telegram
- Scrapbook 37, 1959-1961; Fixed Items (Box 20)
  Includes: Calendar, Cards, Correspondence, Investiture Proceedings, Newspaper Clippings, Parents’ Weekend Schedule, Programs, Rosaverian Newsletter
- Scrapbook 38, 1970-1971; Fixed Items (Box 21)
  Includes: “Faculty Day” Schedule, Anniversary Announcement, Brochures, Concert Programs, Correspondence, Keynote Magazines, Newspaper Clippings, Photos
- Scrapbook 39, 1970-1971; Fixed Items (Box 21)
  Includes: Class Offerings, Convocation Program, Foreign Study Brochure, Newspaper Clippings, Theatre Programs
- Scrapbook 40, 1970; Fixed Items (Box 21)
  Includes: Convocation Program, Keynote Magazine, Newspaper Clippings
  Miele, Alphonse, (5th President)
- Scrapbook 41, 1935-1940; Not a scrapbook: loose materials in box; Lehner, Margaret Yaggle, (1939) (Box 22)
  Includes: Invitations, Newspaper Clippings, Programs
- Scrapbook 42, 1966; Fixed Items (Box 23)
  Includes: Inaugural Materials, Invitations, Keynote Magazine, Letters of Congratulation, Letters of Regret, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs
  Keeshan, Margaret, Sister, (4th President)
- Scrapbook 43, 1976-1981; Mostly fixed items, some loose items; Wysolmerski, Theresa, Sister, (1953) (Box 24)
  Includes: High School Science Program Materials, Lecture Programs, Newsletters, Notes on Graduates, Papers, Photographs
  College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Science Department.; Biology Courses and Students
- Scrapbook 44, 1966; Mostly Fixed Items, some loose (Box 25)
  Includes: Committee for Inauguration Materials, Correspondence, Invitation, Keynote Magazine, Photographs, Program, Rosaverian, Thank You Forms
  Keeshan, Margaret, Sister, (4th President); Presidential Inaugurations
- Scrapbook 45, 1971; Fixed Items (Box 26)
  Includes: Convocation Program, Inaugural Committee Materials, Invitation, Letter of Thanks, Letters of Congratulation, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs
  Miele, Alphonse, (5th President); Presidential Inaugurations
- Scrapbook 46, 1983; Fixed Items; Loose Items in Envelope (Box 27)
  Includes: Inaugural Materials, Letters of Greeting, Newspaper Clippings
  Vaccaro, Louis, (7th President); Presidential Inaugurations
- Scrapbook 47, 1981; Fixed Items; Binding Cracked; Singer, Ann Bartlett, (1981) (Box 28)
  Master's Project: includes Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Printed Material
  College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Art Department.; Student Work
- Scrapbook 48, undated; Fixed Items; College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Student Affairs. (Box 28)
  Includes: Photographs for brochures
- Scrapbook 49, 1956; Many loose items [possibly some missing]; Fixed Items (Box 29)
  Seminar for American Teachers of German materials: including Music Programs, Photographs, Tickets, Travel Stickers
  German Studies Faculty; Seminars, Symposia, and Workshops
- Scrapbook 50, 1965; Fixed Items; Kearney, Alice Teresa, Sister (Box 29)
  Includes: Itinerary, Participant List, Photographs, Postcards
- Scrapbook 51, 1965; Fixed Items; Kearney, Alice Teresa, Sister (Box 29)
  Includes: Airplane Tickets, Brochures, Diary, Menus, Photographs, Postcards, Theatre Programs
- Scrapbook 52, 1962; Fixed Items; Wooden Cover (Box 30)
  Includes: Essays, Magazine Articles, Newspaper Clippings, Pamphlets
  Vatican II
- Scrapbook 53, 1980; Fixed Items; Tarricone, Ronnie N. (Box 31)
  Master's Project: including essays, photographs
- Scrapbook 54, 1956; Fixed Items; Binding Cracked (Box 32)
  Includes: Map, Memorabilia, Photographs, Telegram
- Scrapbook 55, 1980; Fixed Items; Yarbrow-Medina, Teri (Box 32)
  Includes: Paper Materials, Photographs
  College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Art Department.; Art Exhibits
- Scrapbook 56, c. 1971; Fixed Items [Some missing?] (Box 33)
  Includes: Photographs, Postcards
- Scrapbook 57, 1972; Fixed Items; Neat, Charles Marie, Sister (Box 33)
  Includes: Maps, Memorabilia, Pamphlets, Photographs, Postcards
  United States Trips
- Scrapbook 58, 1936; Fixed Items (Box 34)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Programs
  Class of 1936
- Scrapbook 59, 1982-1988; Fixed Items (Box 35)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings, Funeral Cards
  Deceased Alumni and Faculty
- Scrapbook 60, 1982-1988; Fixed Items (Box 36)
  Includes: Newspaper Clippings
  Wedding Announcements
- Scrapbook 61, 1980; Fixed Items; Vatalaro, Paula (Box 36)
  Master's Project: includes Paper Materials, Photographs
- Scrapbook 62, 10/1954-6/1955; Fixed Items; Sister Antonia (Box 37)
  Includes: Funeral Card, Postcards
- Scrapbook 63, 1983-1984; Fixed Items; McCormick, Pauline, Sister (Box 37)
  Includes: Photographs
  Sisters of Saint Joseph of Carondelet.; 125th Anniversary of CSJ Albany Province
- Scrapbook 64, 1958-1959; Fixed Items; College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Student Affairs. (Box 38)
  Includes: Bids, Newspaper Clippings, Paint Samples, Photographs, Programs, Resident List, Wallpapers Samples
  Rose of Lima Hall (366A Western Avenue)
- Scrapbook 65, 1993; Fixed Items; College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Student Affairs. (Box 38)
  Includes: Valentine's Day Party photographs
  Holiday Celebrations
- Scrapbook 66, 1989-1992; Fixed Items (some loose pages); College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Student Affairs. (Box 39)
  Student Events
- Scrapbook 67, c. 1987; Fixed Items (some loose pages); College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Student Affairs. (Box 40)
- Scrapbook 68, 1997; Fixed Items; College of Saint Rose (Albany, N.Y.). Student Affairs. (Box 40)
  Includes: Flyer, Newsletter, Photographs
  Rocky Horror Picture Show
- Scrapbook 69, undated; Pontillo, Richard; Wysolmerski, Theresa, Sister, (1953) (Box 41)
  Biology Courses and Students; Field Trips
- Scrapbook 70, undated; Pontillo, Richard; Wysolmerski, Theresa, Sister, (1953) (Box 41)
- Scrapbook 71, 1991 (Box 42)
  Scheppach, Margaret; Tippett, Michael; Tippett Festival (April 4-7, 1991)